hi this is staff and welcome to my
channel in this channel we talked about
personal finance productivity and
adulting in general so if you're
interested in these topics please
subscribe to this channel hit the
notification Bell like this video and
share this to your
[Music]
friends in this video I would like to
discuss the different life insurances
that are affordable for you to
know so basically we will discuss the
different types of insurances what are
their purpose and
if
insur it is best suited for
them
[Music]
AG life insurances so basically
purpose death benefits dependence or
beneficiaries if
ever or if something happens to you life
insurance guys protection as to for
example
Riders protection against critical
illnesses or other for example accidents
disabilities so but traditionally life
insurance for death benefits if
ever but
now life insurance for
protection savings and investment
components but you also need to know
traditional life insurances or term
insurances whole life
insurances
considerations in when you buy your life
insurance number one you need to know
the insurance coverage that you need so
how much coverage is it 1 million 2
million 3 million so you assess how much
second how long do you want to be
insured so it really depends on the age
for example insured until
50 until
60 whole life until age 70 100 so you
can choose that one number three that
you need to consider is how much you can
afford s premiums or how how much are
you willing to pay for the
premiums amount premiums guys based on
your age based on the amount of your
coverage
based health history so factors that you
need also to consider or the insurance
company needs to
consider am premiums and number four
that you need to consider is whether you
want protection only death benefits for
example or you want to have additional
savings or invest component so so there
are two common types of life insurances
so traditional insurance so under the
traditional insurance term life
insurance and then whole life insurance
and
then is vul or the variable unit life
insurance so
insur for protection but you can add
additional savings or investment
component however guys I would like to
emphasize that life insurance is not
mainly for investment so it is okay that
you get a vul or the variable life
insurance provided that you understand
what it really means or what's the
purpose of it so if if thinking MO vul
is for investment mainly for investment
then I think you got the wrong
investment vehicle purpose life
insurance is mainly for protection if
additional savings and investment
component okay
inv you will get
frr return might as well be
aware addal savings and investment
compon on the side main focus is life
insurance or protection I mentioned guys
about term insurance so for me favorite
type of
insurance you get protected at a bigger
coverage for example
limited budget so okay for me the
downside guys is you're only protected
for a limited number of years or period
based
however but
then amount of Premium once so for
example if term coverage is up to 5
years for another 5 years set amount of
premiums so for example term insurance
is good for 10 years coverage so if for
another 10
years amount premium the good thing
about term insurance is you can also add
Riders to this one so term insurance
from sunlife so it's not sponsored Rider
so for example accident
disability and term insur coupl with
critical illness so same insurance but I
will discuss this one on a later part
now so ter Insurance guysa savings or
investment component because mainly it
is for protection
pricey Focus Life protection death
benefits mainly so for example amount
policy is 1 million for a 1 million
coverage investment component savings
component you can just have this amount
of coverage at a lower price so later
how much premiums
b lower talaga guys compared V with the
whole life insurance Nam guys the
coverage is lifelong okay lifelong
protection and
then 100
years insance Whole Life protection is
up to 100 years old so you just need to
keep up with the premium payments and
then with whole life insurance cash
value so for example starting age
60 cash value or payouts so div
pays
comp V in the sense flating returns
fixed
amount at the end of a specific period
with v guys the investment component
varies it is possible return dep for
example is it in the stocks in bonds
markets affected investment component so
that's why
inv so going back term
insur insur so again I would like to
emphasize that it is mainly for
protection guys so bigger amount of
coverage Focus protection only so other
components like savings and investment
so term insurances is good for newly
married couples especially if child
dependent you can be insured limited
budget so amount of coverage so in
relation to that this is good for
lowincome earners so for
examplei like for
V mon limited amount coverage go for
term insurance so I would say ask the
life insurance
agent term
insurance so you just need to ask
term insurance protected this is also
good for estate tax plan so for example
properties
so
for so of
course estate taxes so term insurance is
goodover payment estate taxes and so on
and so forth and lastly this is good to
increase the amount of coverage for your
life insurance cases guys
V coverage 1 million coverage for
Vance
prote insurance coverage protection so I
have here the list of the best term
insurance consider if ever you want to
get a life insurance so affordable tal
term insurance so you can can ask your
agent from different
companies so you can have Sun safer life
from Sun Life you also have Sun Life
assure from Sun Life meron from PR life
which is called PR life your term and
then from
Phil Guardian policies so you can ask
from the agent for FWD they have FWD set
for tomorrow and then for AXA they have
a Flex seat protect and for manula life
they have the yrt or the yearly
renewable term life insurance and then
lastly for from BPI they have philam
life protector and in the next video
guys discuss term insurance which is
called Sun Life assure
so needs and preferences so if you are
the type of
person savings and investment component
insurance
return two in one so you can go for V
manage your
expectations investment component it is
possible or L earnings from the expected
return AG so just manage your
expectations but if wider or greater
coverage at a lower
price other investment vehicles you can
get term insurances sotion list of term
insurances consider that
one life insurance
coverage so that's it guys remember that
the best life insurance depends on your
purpose your goals and your needs so
assess assess and
assess and ask financial advisors or
life insurance
agents they need or they are responsible
in explaining to you policy or life
insurance hope you learned a lot from
this video
questions feel free to comment down
below and please do not forget to
subscribe to this Channel and share this
to your friends that then if you find
this helpful see you again in my next
Vlog bye